Ladies and gentlemen, good evening and a
very warm welcome to the ICICI Lumbard
General Insurance Company Limited's Q4
and FY 2026 earnings conference call.
From the senior management, we have with
us today Mr. Sanjiv Mantri MD and CEO of
the company. Mr. Gopal Balachandran,
CFO,
Mr. Anand Singhi, Chief Retail and
Government. Mr. Girishes Nayak Chief
Enterprise AI and Technology
Mr. Sep Gurada Chief Corporate Solutions
International and Bank assurance
Mr. Gorav Aurora chief commercial lines
and motor underwriting and claims
and Mr. Girishes Seagal Chief Health UW
and claims customer service and
operations.
Please note that any statements or
comments made in today's call that may
look like forward-looking statements are
based on information presently available
to the management and do not constitute
an indication of any future performance
as the future involves risks and
uncertainties which could cause results
to differ materially from current views
being expressed.
As a reminder, all participants lines
will be in the listenonly mode and there
will be an opportunity for you to ask
questions after the presentation
concludes.
Should you need assistance during this
conference, please signal an operator by
pressing star then zero on your
touchtone phone.
Please note that this conference is
being recorded.
I now hand the conference over to Mr.
Sanjie Mantri, MD and CEO ICIC Lumbard
General Insurance Limited. Thank you and
over to you sir.
>> Thank you.
>> Good evening to each one of you. Thank
you for joining the earnings conference
call of ICSA Lombard for quarter 4 and
financial year 2026.
I would like to commence with an
overview of the economic and industry
trends which have shaped the operating
environment over past few months coupled
with insights on a company's performance
and a key initiatives. Following that,
our CFO Gopal Valatan will take you
through the company's financial
performance for quarter 4 and financial
year 2026.
The quarter gone by has been an eventful
one. For the first two months, the
Indian economy exhibited continued
momentum of growth from the previous
quarter. Whereas the month of March 2026
has seen has been unprecedented in terms
of the geopolitical challenges. The
ongoing conflict in West Asia has
heightened global economic uncertaintity
leading to volatility in energy prices
and financial markets. These external
risks could have some spillover effects
on the Indian economy warranting a
measured and washful approach. That
being said, India's macroeconomic
fundamentals today are considerably
strong and more resilient than in
previous periods of global stress. This
provides a degree of comfort in our
ability to absorb external shocks.
Although we remain mindful of evolving
global conditions,
let me now dwell upon the ensuing
quarter and the year gone by. Retail
sales of private cars, two wheelers and
tractors remained positive for the year.
In accordance with the data reported by
WAN for financial year 2026, the sales
growth of private car and two wheeler
stood at healthy 11.9% and 13.2%
respectively.
Pertinently for H2 2026 the sales growth
of private car and two wheeler stood at
17.8 and 21.5 as against 4.6 and 3.2
respectively in H1 2026 led by GST
rationalization.
This continued momentum is also seen in
quarter 4 2026 wherein the growth of
private car and two-wheeler stood at a
healthy 16.3 and 24.7% respectively.
Also noteworthy was the fact that two
wheeler sales surpassed surpassed their
their pre-COVID peak and were at a
decadal high.
Even the sales of commercial vehicle
based the data reported by WAN have
witnessed a growth of 20.2% in H2 2026
versus 14.9%
for H1 2026 and a fullear growth of
12.9%.
Given the early trends of numbers
reported by certain banks, credit growth
is expected to be in double digit for
quarter 4 2026 with broad-based
expansion across segments. Also, vehicle
vehicle financing continued to be an
important contributor to credit growth
broadly in line with the trends observed
in retail automoil sales.
We believe that the above factors
augment well for the industry in time to
come. Moving to the regulatory update.
You may be aware that IRDA has mandated
insurers to prepare and present their
financial statements in accordance with
the applicable Indas effective 1st April
2026. View we view this as a positive
step as the enhanced disclosure
requirements under India's framework
will meaningfully improve transparency
and align the reporting standards of
Indian insurers with global practices.
While the regulator requires insurers to
provide the reporting as per both India
and Indian GAP for 2027 and 2028, it has
provided the insurer the option of
seeking forbearance to transitioning the
statutory accounting to India's for the
first year. We've examined the option
provided by the authority and it
believed it would be appropriate to seek
the forbearance in order to ensure that
the transition is executed in a
calibrated and oper operationally robust
manner.
Another important initiative announced
by the authority is the public insurance
registry which is expected to become a
key pillar of India's digital public
infrastructure.
As the framework evolves, PIR has the
potential to support industry growth by
improving penetration, driving
efficiency, elevating customer service
and also enabling better risk selection
across ecosystem. We believe that over
time it will also enhance transparency,
strengthen trust and create enduring
benefit for the policy holder, insurers
and the broader financial system.
Let me now dwell upon the industry
performance for the year ended March
31st, 2026.
The general insurance industry reported
a GDPI growth of 9.2% for 2026.
Excluding crop and market segment, the
gross GDPI growth stood at 13.3% for
2026.
Speaking of the specific segments within
the industry, the commercial segment
reported a growth of 12.2% for 2026.
However, if one was to break down this
growth into H1 and H2, the growth was
14.2 and 9.6% respectively.
As one observes, the business witnessed
elevated level of competitive intensity
and pricing pressure especially in the
fire segment in the second half of the
year leading to muted growth.
The renews of April 1st, 2026 also are
being reported at a discount to the
previous year reflecting that this trend
is likely to continue for quarter 1 2027
as well. On the positive side, however,
we also would like to mention that the
in the reinsurance renewals for
financial year 2027 have been soft.
The motor segment growth for the
industry stood at 9.2% 2% for financial
year 2026 with the momentum experience
post the GST rationalization the second
half of the year has witnessed improved
growth levels of 10 and a half with the
first half which stood at 7.6%.
The health segment including mass health
grew by 15.4% for 2026 which makes it
the fastest growing segment for last
five years for from financial year 2022
to 2026.
Within this the group has line of
business view at 12.8% for 2026 whereas
the retail health g growth stood at
19.9% for 2026.
Speaking on the underwriting performance
of the industry overall the combined
ratio of the industry deteriorated from
113.2% in 9 month financial year 2025 to
119.3
in 9 month 2026. The overall combined
ratio for private players remained
relatively flattish for from triple 1.2%
for the period 9 month 2025 to triple
1.5%
for the period 9 month 2026. Due to fing
combined ratio for the motor line of
business continue to remain elevated at
128.1%
for 9 month 2026 with 123.8% 8% for the
period ended 9 month 2025.
I will now proceed to present our
company's performance across key
business segments for 2026. The company
reported a growth of 7% in gross
domestic premium income for 2026
compared to the industry growth of 9.2%
for the same period. ICS Lombard
achieved a growth of 18.2% 2% and 15.7%
in quarter 4 and H2 2026 respectively
against an industry growth of 10.9 and
11.2% over the same period.
However, as the crop and market segment
the company recorded a growth of 10.2%
2% and for financial year 2026 by the
industry view at 13.3% for the same
period.
In the commercial line segment, our
growth stood at 5.4% for financial year
2026 as again compared to industry
growth of 12.2% for 2026.
During H1 2026, our growth in commercial
lines stood at 6.5% versus industry
growth of 14.2%.
Wills for H2 2026 growth level stood at
3.8%
versus industry growth of 9.6%.
ADM amidst competitive pressure we
continue to drive profitable growth
through prudent underwriting and
judicious risk selection through our
multi- channelannel distribution. We
continue to maintain leadership position
in liability and marine cargo line of
business for financial year 2026.
In motor segment, our growth stood at
7.6% 6% for financial year 2026 as again
the industry growth of 9.2% for the same
period. In H1 of 2026 we grew at 2.2% in
the motor segment versus the industry
growth which grew at 7.6%.
However, H2 of 2026 we exceeded the
growth level of industry by 1 and a
half% in motor that is 12% which is the
industry growth of 10.5%.
This momentum was evident in quarter 4
of financial year 2026 where we achieved
a growth of 15% with while the industry
grew at 10%.
Our portfolio mix for private carer and
combined and commercial vehicles stood
at 52.8 25.4 and 21.8% respectively for
financial year 2026.
In the health segment for 2026, we grew
by 20% as against the industry growth of
15.4%
on a 1 byN basis.
For quarter 4 2026, the growth stood at
a robust 38.2%
as again the industry growth of 20.5%.
Our retail sales business continue to
demonstrate strong growth of 51.1%
for 2026 significantly outpacing the
industry growth of 19.9% in the same
period.
Consequently, a market share has
improved from 3.3% in financial year
2025 to 4.1% in financial year 2026.
For the year, the company has seen a 2x
growth in the new retail health
indemnity business source compared to
the previous year. Our share of
long-term premiums in new business for
retail health stands at 42.1%
for financial year 2021, up from 28.5%
for financial year 2025. This
performance has been driven by on
ongoing product innovation and sustained
investment in strengthening our real
health distribution franchise or retail
health uh distribution franchise.
For the overall group health portfolio
portfolio, we continue to maintain a
disciplined approach with a focus on
managing the book effectively. The group
health segment recorded a growth of 11%
for financial year 2026 over 2025 with a
market share being 8.7% for financial
year 2026.
We have kept a focus on augmenting cash
flows through underlying long-term
business in various line of business.
Our advanced premium in motor insurance
has increased by over 15% in financial
year 2026 with financial year 2025.
A market share in advanced premium
excluding motor share stands at 12.5%
for financial year 2026 up from 9.6%
from financial year 2025.
Our discipent focus on profitable growth
has helped us deliver consistent
outcomes over time. When market
fluctuations may impact performance in
individual quarters, our track record
reflects our ability to navigate cycles
and deliver value over the long term. If
we analyze the 10-year time horizon from
financial year 2020 2016 to 2025, it is
pertinent to note that the company's
average combined ratio stood at 102.9%
reflecting sustained underwriting
discipline across various market
conditions. This would compare favor
favorably with the industry average of
115.3%
over the same period.
Furthermore, our investment performance
has also remained strong. Over the same
10 year uh 10 year horizon, we delivered
a robust average realized yield of 8.7%
supported by prudent assent asset
allocation and effective capital
management over multiple cycles. This in
turn has translated into an healthy
average return on equity of 19.1% over
the 10-year period which would compare
favorably against the industry average
ROE of 4%.
Reinforcing the strength and resilience
of our overall business model and
consistency of our execution. Our one
and one team philosophy continues to
foster collaboration and operational
excellence
enabling a unified approach across the
organization.
As a part of this philosophy, we'll now
apprise you of certain key initiatives.
First, I would like to highlight a
strategic capability we have built in
house. One that materially strengthens
our execution engine. We call it IL1
force.
RL Force is an enterprise productivity
platform which has been in operation for
over a year and is used by over 10,000
sales employees. It is on track to
become the single operating platform for
all our 15,000 employees across the
organization.
L14 indicates work execution,
performance management, collaboration
and recognition into a single platform,
simplifying operations, reinforcing
execution, discipline, and driving
accountability with real time enterprise
wide wide visibility.
The platform enables structured partner
engagement, task management, and
real-time performance analytics across
the partner life cycle. Its renewal
capability has improved conversion by 5%
while enhanced engagement with and while
enhanced engagement has doubled partner
participation and expanded market reach.
Notably in health indemnity improved
engagement led to a 2x increase in agent
activation and a doubling of new retail
business.
Our picture app, a one-stop solution for
insurance and wellness needs, achieved
21 million downloads as of 31st March
2026, reflecting the growing customer
engagement and digital adoption. The GWP
earned from the Takeare app during the
period 2026 was 51 5170 million with the
corresponding premium earning for 2025
which stood at 2237.2
million. From a claim intimation
perspective, 67% of the customers now
intimate their health reimbursement
claims through the app. While 82% of the
claim intimation of a travel product,
Trip Secure Plus went through Take care
app. We will continue to focus on
improving the service experience of a
customer with a single simplified
interface for their insurance
requirements. We continue to improve our
efficiency level in motor claims too.
Our preferred partner network service
75.5% of our nonoem claims for quarter 4
2026 respectively up from 74.1% for
quarter 4 2025. For 9 months we recorded
an NPS of 69 for motor claims.
In the retail segment 98.8% of our total
claims were paid within 30 days for
financial year 2026. For the 9 month
2026 on a count basis the number stood
at 99.9%
with the corresponding number from the
industry being at 82.1%.
For rind one 2026 we recorded an NPS of
73 for health claims demonstrating
strong satisfaction level and
reinforcing our position as a
customercentric organization.
IELTS has further strengthened our on
ground claim supports for our health
customers and our customer coverage
improving by 25% over the previous year.
As a part of their feedback, 95% of our
customer survey rated their experience
as exemplary highlighting the support
provided during case processing and
assistance with hospital coordination.
This reaffirms our focus on
best-in-class service to our customers
during the moment that truly matters.
The one and one call center initiative
continues to deliver strong momentum in
the company's transition toward the
digital first do-it-yourself service
model. In March 2026, more than five
lakh service engagements, 69% of the
total service engagements were executed
digitally. Our differentiated service
initiatives which we have spoken about
in previous earnings call have resulted
in increase of our call center NPS to 74
in quarter 4 2026 from 60 in quarter 1
2026.
Before I close the current year marks an
important milestone in the journey of
ICI Lumbar. As we enter into our 25th
year of operations, we would like to
take this opportunity to express our
heartfelt gratitude to all our stake
stakeholders who have been truly who has
truly supported us in our journey so far
and we look forward to your continued
trust, encouragement and support in the
years ahead. I will now request Gupal to
take you through the financial numbers
for quarter 4 and financial year 2026.
Thanks Anjie and uh good evening to each
one of you. I will now give you a brief
overview of the financial performance of
the recently concluded quarter in the
full financial year. We have uploaded
the results presentation on our website.
You can access it as we walk you through
the performance numbers with effect from
October 1, 2024. Long-term products are
accounted on a 1 byN basis as mandated
by the regulator IID. Please refer our
investor presentation slide number 16
for the further details on comparison of
financials on a on an n and 1 byn basis.
It may be noted that all the numbers
that I will be speaking about are on a 1
byn basis unless otherwise mentioned.
On combined ratio our combined ratio on
an n basis for fi26 was 102.4%.
As against 102.6% 6% in FI25.
Our combined ratio on a 1 byN basis for
the current year was 103.4 as against
102.8% in FI25.
Excluding the impact of wage code of
rupees 55 billion. The combined ratio
for FI26 stood at 102.1%.
And 103.1%
on a N basis and 1 byN basis
respectively. Our combined ratio on a n
basis for quarter 4 was 10.5
as against 102.1 in quarter 4 of fi25.
Our combined ratio on a 1 by n basis for
quarter 4 current year was 101.2
as against 102.5 in quarter 4 of last
year. On the investments, our investment
assets during the quarter rose to rups
584.21 21 billion as at March 31, 2026,
up from rupes 582.96 billion as at
December 31, 2025.
Our investment leverage net of
borrowings was at 3.48 times at March
31, 2026
and at 3.6 times as at December 31,
2025. Investment income was at rupees
47.42 billion in FI26 as against rupees
42.5 billion in FI25.
On a quarterly basis, investment income
was at rupees 9.85 billion in Q4 this
year as against rupes 8.77 billion in Q4
last year. During the quarter under
review, the company has recognized we
have a policy on impairment of uh
investment assets. Uh basis that the
company has recognized an impairment on
its equity portfolio investments of
rupees.49
49 billion in this quarter for FI26
versus a small ride back that we had of
almost about 3 crores uh that we had in
quarter 4 of uh the last financial year
driven by the prevailing market
correction. Now coming to profitability
our profit before tax grew by 10.2% to
rupes 36.59 billion in FI26 as against
rupes 33.21 21 billion in FI25
excluding the impact of the wage code
that I referred earlier of rupees 0.55
billion the PBT grew by 11.8% to rupees
37.14 billion in FI26
our PBT grew by 7.5% to rupees 7.18
billion in Q4 FI26 as against rupees
6.68 68 billion in Q4 FI25 on the profit
after tax. Therefore, consequently on a
1 byN basis, the PAD grew by 10.5% to
rupees 27.72 billion in FI26 as against
rupees 25.08 billion in FI25.
Again excluding the impact of the wage
code, the PAT on a 1 byN basis grew by
12.2% to rupees 28.14 billion in FI26.
On an end basis, PAT grew by 14.1% to
rupees 27.61 billion in FI26. That's
against rupees 24.19 billion in FI25.
On an end basis, excluding the impact of
the wage code, the PAD grew by 15.9% to
rupees 28.03 billion in FI26.
Our PAT on a 1 byN basis grew by 7.3% to
5.47 billion in Q4 this year as against
rupees 5.1 billion in Q4 last year. Same
numbers on an end basis PAD grew by
15.6% to to rupees 5.39 billion in Q4
FI26 as against 4.66 billion in Q4 FI25.
Coming to return on average equity or
ROE was 17.8% in FI26 as against 19.1%
in FI25
excluding the impact of wage code of
rupees.55 billion. The ROE stood at
18.1%
for FI26.
ROE for quarter 4 current year was at
13.3%.
As again 14.5% in Q4 FI25.
Coming to dividend, the board of
directors of the company has proposed a
final dividend of 7 per share for FI26.
This payment is however subject to
approval of shareholders in the encing
general annual general meeting of the
company. The overall dividend for FI26
including the above proposed final
dividend is rupes 13.5 per share. Last
year the overall dividend was rupes 12.5
per share. On solveny we continue to
exhibit a very healthy solveny ratio of
2.67 times at March 31st 2026 as against
2.69 at December 31 2025 which continues
to be higher than the minimum regulatory
requirement. The solvency of course was
impacted by roughly about 14 basis
points as an outcome of the marktomarket
loss position that we had on the equity
book as at March 31, 2026. As I
conclude, I would like to state that we
are aligned with our ethos of driving
profitable growth. Consistent and
sustainable value creation for all our
stakeholders while ensuring that the
interest of policy holders are at the
forefront at all times. I would like to
thank you all for attending this
earnings call and we will now be happy
to take questions that you may have.
Thank you.
Thank you very much. We will now begin
the question and answer session. Anyone
who wishes to ask a question may press
star and one on their touchdown
telephone. If you wish to remove
yourself from the question Q, you may
press star and two. Participants are
requested to please use handsets while
asking a question. Ladies and gentlemen,
we will now wait for a moment while the
question queue assembles.
Our
first question comes from the line of
Supratin Duta from Jeff. Please go
ahead.
Hello. Um, thanks a lot for the
opportunity. My first question is on the
competitive environment in the industry.
Uh, there have been articles recently
indicating that competition in the
commercial lines have been fairly
elevated to indicated that you know the
motor lines combined ratio remains
elevated. So if you could give us an
idea about you know how competitive
environment in the different segments is
panning out that would be helpful and is
there any improvement due to now uh the
um guidelines kicking in. So that's my
first question. The second question
coming to the loss ratio side uh this
year fourth quarter motor TTP loss ratio
has been significantly lower than what
we have seen in the last uh years in uh
fourth quarter motor TPT loss ratio. So
just wanted to understand you know what
has played out for this uh significant
improvement versus the run rate that we
have seen previously and why is the pop
loss ratio negative if you could give
some color on that. Lastly on IFRS Gopal
you know would it be possible for you to
give us some understanding or clarity
regarding you know how your PAT under
IFRS would look versus the IGAP pat um
that would be very helpful. Thank you.
You'll take the second one first.
>> Maybe I can take the second and the
third and then maybe I can ask maybe
Sanjiv can respond the first one. Um I
think on the loss ratio supraim I think
uh this obviously comes to us every
quarters and I think our response will
still remain the same as in to say that
one you have to keep looking at motor as
a category as compared to one looking at
separately uh motor own damage and third
party. That's one. Second, I think we
would continue to again request all of
you to keep looking at numbers more on
uh full year basis as compared to let's
say any given quarter. And uh just to
kind of refresh what we have been
telling the street is I think the range
that we're comfortable on motor is
between 65 to 67. I think that is the
range that we have maintained and if you
could have seen for the full year
current year I think we ended at roughly
about 66.3%.
it's well within that range and hence to
that extent I think that's the range
that we would be kind of tracking pretty
closely. Uh so in that sense there is
nothing that has kind of changed. Uh if
you ask us has has any of our reserving
philosophy undergone a change the short
answer is no and we continue to kind of
maintain prudence uh in terms of
maintaining our uh loss reserves. So
hence uh I think we keep looking at
numbers more on full year basis as
compared to any given quarters. So
that's one crop. Uh I think again uh
time and again we have kind of talked
about it because generally again just to
kind of refresh most of the businesses
in crop get booked around quarter 2 and
somewhere around quarter 3 and maybe
early quarter four because those are
typically the two seasons that largely
get exhibited. In our case, we had
predominantly a large exposure on crop
largely from one state of which a large
part of our premium was something that
had got kind of booked roughly around
quarter two of the year and as we have
said it obviously takes time for the
season to kind of play out in terms of
actual loss experiences and in any in
any quarter when you see that experience
play out then to that extent obviously
and if you recollect even at the time of
booking the uh policies we obviously
follow a very very conservative approach
of providing for almost 100% % loss
ratio at the time of writing the risk
and as the actual experiences play out
obviously to that extent in case if you
see some kind of a positive change then
to that extent that gets reflected again
in the given uh quarter and hence to
that extent is why possibly you are
seeing that number uh in line with the
loss ratio outcomes for quarter 4 here
again I would continue to urge that you
should again look at the numbers more on
a full year basis on a full year basis
is pretty much kind of range bound
whether you look at FI25 or whether
whether you look at FI26. Um on India's
I think uh uh in line with what we had
also kind of put out as a part of the
opening uh transcript um at this point
of time uh given the state at uh which
uh so one if you ask us is the now now
that is now there is a definitive uh uh
date uh in so far as uh transitioning to
India is concerned so hence that's a
very very welcome step in so far as the
overall uh industry is concerned. I
think that's what rightfully so the
regulator has done it. Um in terms of uh
uh our own transition I think we do have
uh we have been working on a plan of
action in terms of getting our uh
processes internally uh up and ready so
that we are able to kind of start
reporting uh numbers to all of you uh uh
whenever we are kind of ready for it. Um
at this point of time I think we will
continue to kind of give uh in line with
what we have done even in the past we
have been submitting performer numbers
uh for the last two years. So we will
continue even for 262 27 on a quarterly
basis in line with the requirements we
will continue to submit uh India India's
based results to the regulator and maybe
we will come back to all of you at an
appropriate time uh and then we will
possibly start talking about more
specifics in terms of the impact that it
does on both uh the combined ratios and
maybe the return on equity objectives
because those are the two two things
that the market obviously kind of wants
to hear from us. So we will come back on
that uh and maybe on the first point so
also you know from the just to close out
the FRS part and we've always said in
the past also that uh the year of
adoption there would be a significant
decline combined ratio it can be in the
range of 300 basis to you know maybe 400
450 basis point but look that's only the
accounting part of it economic value
over a period of time it is expected to
converge and have the same uh you know
uh value creation for the company as it
happens. So, so our stand pretty much
remains same and yes from next quarter
one we would end up doing our submission
on that count. Uh with respect to super
on the comp competitive pressure that is
there and we spoke about that also when
we were giving the overall briefing for
the year that has gone by yes it has
intensified on commercial business. uh
at the same time the the capacity
overall on the reinsurance side was very
high available and we've been able to
see to some extent it getting negated.
Uh will this continue? My my own belief
is market forces will play out but our
own understanding is when we see
intensive competition the selection has
to get sharper uh because it's will we
compete in the market? Answer is yes. uh
but uh what we've been able to write and
what we will write we will be creating
differentiation if you remember last
year even in you know over quarters we
had said that there was a marginal loss
of uh market share for us on the fire
side purely was on account of the fact
that uh we will do what is comfortable
and the output is in some ways here to
see these are all very exposure-driven
products and you have to be cautious of
what you pick and what you don't and we
continue to follow at uh there is no
overarching worry. We are very well
placed as an institution in terms of
what practices we have to counter any
such measures that come up in the market
and overall insurance general insurance
in particular have seen uh these kind of
conduct at multiple levels and we are
well pleased about it. On motor also in
a similar vein uh yes the industry is
been uh stretched at multiple counts.
the combined ratio which I just spoke
about for the 9 months stayed at 128
clearly not a workable one we continue
to pick and choose and deliver
uh a result which is differentiated from
the market it's purely led by on
multiple count distribution and
underwriting practices which
differentiates in own damage as well as
third party which briefly you know Gopal
spoke about thank you
>> understood perfectly thank Sure.
>> Thank you. Thanks.
>> Thank you. Our next question comes from
the line of Pra Jen from Motila Losal.
Please go ahead.
>> Yeah. Hi everyone. Uh two questions from
my side. Firstly, if I just wanted to
take a view on your solvency which is
like uh very high at 2.7. How do you
think that you will uh whether you
because you've been generating good
profits over the past few years and in
fact from FI22 to FI25
and even now the solveny has been
increasing. So how do you see you know
whether you can utilize the solvency
better in terms of paying out dividends
or in any other form uh to kind of
because and unless the growth is really
exceptional we I'm sure that we wouldn't
need that kind of excess solveny on the
balance sheet that's question number one
second you know we've been talking about
motor TP price hike and uh you know
we've discussed this in the last call
last few calls as well but given the
trajectory on the motor TP loss ratios
at about 63 3.2 in FI25 and 63.8 this
year for you. Do you think that uh you
know motor DP price hike can uh come in?
Um and my last question is on on the
health insurance point. Uh uh Gopal if
you could split up the loss ratios for
retail retail and group.
>> Yeah. Yeah. So maybe yeah. Uh so uh so
pre uh uh so the first one I think uh um
I think as a company uh what we have
always maintained is uh uh sufficient uh
margins when it comes to solveny because
uh in uh the Indian market is still on
solvency one regulation I think of
course there is a road map to maybe
eventually transition to risk based
capital which again as what as what the
regulator has rightfully done on India
as I'm sure they would possibly try and
do a similar thing even on a transition
to risk based capital as well. So
obviously one will have to wait and see
how that plays out but till that point
of time I think the Indian market
continues to be guided by solvency one
uh which uh as I said still mandates uh
capital ask to be maintained bases the
gross exposures that you have as an
entity and hence to that extent we'll
have to be uh mindful of and prudent uh
in terms of the levels of solvency that
we carry as an institution. Um having
said that I think uh to your point on uh
the last few years I think uh fair
observation but if you see I think last
couple of years in specific I think we
have been relatively uh lower uh when it
comes when it comes to growth but that's
something that we have already seen a
clear positive uh reversal of trends
emerging for us and with the momentum
that that we have kind of seen in all
fairness one would obviously want to
kind of make sure that we are able to
kind of get it extended uh even as we
head into FI27 and the moment you will
see as what you have seen uh let's say
even uh in the second half of this year
growth kind of coming back uh so to that
action obviously one will uh look at
consuming some part of uh the solveny
that we have and three ours solveny is
also guided by obviously a mix of what
is it that we want to drive in terms of
the growth objective and two at the same
time make sure that we are kind of
appropriately kind of rewarding uh the
investors who have kind of obviously
placed faith in us and in that context I
think if you would have seen
historically we do have a board governed
uh dividend distribution policy in place
uh on an average I think what we have
been able to kind of distribute uh is
roughly about uh 25% of our PAT and this
year again as what we had kind of put
out in our opening transcript roughly
about 13 and a half rupees per share for
the full year roughly translates to
almost about 25% of for profit after
tax. Uh so hence it's obviously will be
a continued combination of both uh
rewarding the shareholders appropriately
and at the same time making sure that we
are able to use the capital for uh
growth. And the three the third part as
I said we will obviously kind of keep a
watch on the transition to risk based
capital. So that's one uh to your point
on the breakup for the health loss ratio
numbers I think yeah thankfully this
time the question has come ahead of time
so so maybe we'll answer it. Uh so I
think uh Q4 of last year this right now
I'll give you the numbers for quarter 4
employer employee book uh the last last
year Q4 the loss ratio was uh 98% and
this year that number is almost the same
at 981%.
On the retail uh indemnity book uh the
loss ratio for Q4 last year was 64.8
and this year quarter 4 the loss ratio
on the indemnity book is at 57.6.
Now the same year numbers on a full year
basis employer employee book for last
year has been at 97.2
and this year full year the employer
employee book loss ratio stands at about
91.9
on the retail indemnity full year last
year was 67.9
this year full year is at about 64.6 six
uh so just that for now to kind of
summit again on the indemnity book I
think the range that we have spoken
about is between 65 to 70% and that's
what we have kind we have been kind of
largely talking through even in the past
several quarters and broadly if you see
the experience that one has seen the
good part is I think one we have been
able to book build a book uh which is
pretty much to our liking and it has
kind of played out both in terms of
growth in market share and also staying
within the loss ratio range so those are
the responses to the two questions maybe
the most third party.
>> So yes uh I think uh possibly it's been
almost 5 years now since the uh industry
has uh got a hike uh at the loss ratio
at the industry level as far as motor TP
is concerned is at around 85 and
thereabouts. uh which is significantly
you know elevated uh where we are we
have been able to uh if you see and
Gopal briefly spoke about it we have to
also reconfigure our portfolio to get
aligned and drive the efficiency uh
which we've been able to reflect uh it
does at time lead to a loss and whenever
we end up having discussions uh whether
individually or collectively there's so
much of you know questioning as to why
has the market share gone gone up that
is what it takes to reconsider. Uh we've
also recalibrated our practice in terms
of ground surveillance and doing what is
required uh to avoid fraud which
probably we would easily say is among
the lowest in the industry. There's no
way we can claim to eliminate it. So
there are multiple factors that go about
it. We remain desirous of the fact that
yes the TP hike for the industry is
overdue and uh sooner than later that
should play out. uh but we can only
control what is in in our hand. This one
definitely is not. And in line with that
we continue to forge our own uh
understanding and deliberation to
penetrate market at multiple counts and
make it work for us uh as a company and
uh from an industry standpoint sooner
than later we do hope the relief comes
through.
>> Thank you. Thank you so much.
>> Thank you. Thanks.
Thank you.
Our next question comes from the line of
Sankit Koda from Aventis Park. Please go
ahead.
>> Uh yeah, thank you. Thank you for the
opportunity. Uh so so my my my first
question is is that last year we we kind
of lost market share in commercial
lines. Um and um and uh given given the
market is soft as you highlighted uh is
it fair to say that uh we we will claw
back kind of a market share in the
software market or we will remain as
cautious as we were last time and and
and in and and and in in in these lines
just wanted to understand given given
the soft market growth outlook uh given
given um your second half growth is
16%age
uh and maybe crop being a new tendering
uh uh tendering uh year uh how do you
see growth of the 16 percentage to
continue for the next year uh and any
any color if you can give on that those
lines will be very useful that that's my
first question maybe maybe I will ask
another one later
>> okay no so no sit I think uh last year
uh I'm saying when you're saying last
year before the one which you just given
the result it's a financial 25 we were
we didn't lose market share we had
gained by 0.1 we had a quarter here we
missed but overall we had gained
We talking about a market share which is
in the range of 13.7 which was year
before last. This year we have closed
by8.7 basis point lower. Uh and it's
driven through multiple configuration
when we meet up personally for I more
than happy to sit run through that uh
these that kind of a share that we draw
these fluctuations to ensure that we
select right can happen. uh but uh the
commercial practice that we have is very
unique uh in the industry and it's not
driven by what business we're able to
write. It's about how we are able to
even manage claims. Uh there's a
significant contribution on large
corporates to mid and to small. Honestly
speaking from an entity standpoint we
have been we have done a much more uh uh
you know recent job on the large
corporate side and over last two to
three years which we have been briefing
to you it's been a more distributionled
growth and we've been able to diversify
our port our portfolio in a in a
significant manner. We do we do believe
that uh we are we have a very
significant edge in the overall practice
and we will be able to uh have a you
know a reasonable presence as far as
commercial is concerned. I don't want to
jump the gun to say uh where the market
share will be but we will be a very
relevant player and it's not uh easy to
see us losing foothold on that on an
overarching basis. crop coming into
play. We will uh and yes the market
opens up significantly. We are still
awaiting the details in terms of on what
contours this market will open as in
when those guidelines come in. Uh we'll
be able to comment as to what it is but
we've always maintained our stand that
crop will be purely on selection. this
is of what we feel is appropriate rather
than a targeted statement where we say
you know that's not the way we look at
it. Uh do we want to participate? It's a
bold yes. Do we want to you know chase
it? The answer is no. Uh we we very well
placed overall to and we're excited
actually in terms of the opportunity
that will present itself. Our current
crop number wizard is what was there
year before last or this year I'll
virtually have and uh uh there is some
play available for us to make it count
in this year.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Sorry.
>> Oh, sorry. You're saying something. Go
ahead. Please go ahead.
>> No, no, sorry. Sorry. you when I meant
uh April last year you lost market share
in commercial lines because you believed
the market was too soft and and if you
are assuming it is too soft again maybe
maybe full year you caught it up but but
but given April is very strong in the
renewal for for uh fire whether whether
whether whether whether it will have any
implication in oneq growth or or April
growth which is which is significantly
very big and lastly
>> yeah go ahead lastly on crop crop just
just wanted to add that uh whether
whether you confined till till last
three years to to one state uh maybe I
don't know what final controls will be
but but it is fair to say that you you
will be expanding beyond a particular
state in in in the current year or not
broadly broadly that's that's way you
are strategically thinking in those
lines or not is the point I wanted to
check
>> yeah yeah so so one state uh worked out
because it was in line of what we wanted
to do it is not a plan that will
continue to be a one state p we will go
uh wherever ever it makes uh you know uh
uh commercial sense and we believe that
it is appropriate and crop obviously can
play out the way it is. We are still
awaiting structure. So there is there is
we are open to whatever that comes up
our way to be very honest on that point
and on the commercial part in terms of
uh uh what you were saying look the
growth of the industry itself will get
impacted and we are we are a sub we are
an offshoot of that. So uh uh we can do
better, we can do worse depending on how
it pans out. Uh uh but overall if you
remember in H1 uh we had a
uh much bigger loss with what happened
in H2. So uh we've also done what is
required uh so what cannot get you know
what cannot be acquired through uh large
corporates we have played out in
distribution has taken its own play but
we are very well entrenched uh so we
should be fine on the commercial part
also overall as an entity
>> understood so from growth point of view
given
>> sorry to interrupt we request you to
please
>> the growth on commercial because of fire
being there the industry itself may have
challenges is on growth. Uh let me uh
put this very clearly. Uh but it doesn't
mean that uh it put us at a significant
disadvantage as anybody else. It would
be probably single digit.
>> Sorry just to squeezing I was asking
that second half our growth was 16%age
though weak in first half. So this 16%
growth run rate uh you expect to
continue largely 4527.
I mean there is so much happening all
around that uh uh how do we predict that
but yes uh Gopal mentioned that very
briefly we're very confident of moving
into the quarter 1 and quarter two on a
positive note overall as things stand
yes we but how does the industry play
out overall uh we will have to watch at
that uh uh we also presume that the the
the tailwind which got huge amount of
GST cut which led to a very robust
quarter four uh would continue to play
out definitely we'll be well placed for
a growth. We we are excited with that
opportunity but we'll have to wait in
terms of how the market plays out. Yeah.
Thank you.
>> Okay. Yeah. Thanks. Yeah.
>> Thank you.
Our next question comes from the line of
Nidesh from Invest. Please go ahead.
>> Thanks for the opportunity sir. My
question is on motor. So in motor in H1
we view lessers in the market in H2 we
view faster in the market. So what drove
that and what is the outlook of our
growth with industry growth in FI27 on
on in the motor segment.
>> Yeah. Okay. So D I think uh yes H S H S
H S H S H S H S H S H S H S H S H2 was
better. There was also uh a significant
play that came out on account of new
sales uh for the country doing better
and uh there is no denial in you know
there's nothing which we can say uh that
we tend to do better when new sales are
uh very high and we have seen that new
grew at almost 18.8%
uh for us with this 13.4 on the old
side.
on the outlook of financial year 27 um
we'll have to see we do expect a higher
singledigit growth at the industry level
and if that happens it would be again uh
good for us and other thing which worked
out last year was the growth of two
biller by when I was talking I said that
it was at a decade high in terms of the
overall growth that happened we for last
three four years we have been saying
that we have not beaten the pre-COVID
number on two billers that itself is
again a big plus uh overall on the uh
motor side. I think the only thing that
I'll just add this just to what Sanji
was saying I think one of the thing
initiatives that we have will also been
speaking in our earlier calls is our
relentless focus on improving retentions
uh and uh we will be very again happy to
kind of uh indicate that uh for the full
year I think at an aggregate let's say
company level a large part of which will
be predominantly let's say retail
business lines I think we have seen an
improvement in our overall retention
numbers go up by almost about 5
percentage points
U so hence that is something that we
will continue to stay focused on even as
we head into FI27. So that will be an
important lever uh that we would
obviously kind of uh uh work on uh
beyond of course the point that Sanjay
made in so far as new vehicle sales is
concerned.
So basically the growth acceleration
that we have seen is a function of
growth new vehicle sales going up and
competitive intensity reducing and we
gaining market share on a lack basis. Uh
so yeah so new and old and I think like
this sometime in quarter one last year
that we had uh as a company extensively
worked on the retention part a lot of
work was done on multiple counts uh by
us and that's what Gopal is referring to
when he's saying that we are a delta of
higher retention of our customers.
>> Sure. So and that so should we expect
cube H2 trend to play out next year also
that we will grow faster than the
industry or
>> uh are I think I think let me put it
this way we we will we are well placed
overall but uh there are multiple
factors see I mean if there's there is a
challenge on the energy if the uh if uh
the Indian mentality moves into the
savings part of it rather than spending
the motor sales or auto sales which
probably all of you are well aware of it
actually ends up getting really muted.
We'll have to see how that part comes
in. Uh but we would say that uh the
momentum on quarter 3 to quarter four
and so effectively in quarter one should
play out. Uh I would say yes we are
going with a very positive mindset at
this point of time.
>> Sure. Uh that's it for myself.
>> Thanks. Thanks. Thanks.
>> Thank you. Our next question comes from
the line of Avin Singh with MK Global.
Please go ahead.
Yeah. Hi. Uh thanks for the opportunity.
Uh good evening. A couple of question.
The first one uh a bit I would uh say if
you can uh clarify my understanding this
49 cr kind of a charge that you have
taken for diminish in value of
investment uh provisions in this quarter
is it largely driven by the equity
market fall or bond or kind of a both.
So that's one and second in motor TP of
course you have experienced a lot of
things. Uh now my question is that okay
we have not seen a sort of a price hype
but what had changed for you that you
have kind of a accelerated your growth
in CV segment. Now typically from
whatever we hear it is a CV by and large
where the price revision is required and
it's not so profitable but in Q4 uh it
seems that you have gone uh a lot higher
in terms of you know uh that CV. So what
has change there? What kind of a
strategy is there? And for the full year
around 780 crores of motor third party
reserve will get uh is that number I'm
seeing correctly. Thanks
>> the last one.
>> So maybe I can take the last one. Uh so
Ain again again we will keep saying uh
you should keep looking at the loss
ratio range that we have spoken about
for motor as a category which is between
65 to 67. an absolute amount of uh
reserve number that you spoke about
honestly uh in our sense is something
that uh would not necessarily be a right
metric to kind of track. A better metric
will be to keep looking at the loss
ratio outcome which is the range that we
have kind of spoken about between 65 to
67. Now the good part is I think uh I
think what has worked for us I think is
I think we have seen a clear rebound of
growth and at the same time we have been
able to maintain the loss ratio
expectations that we have set out. Uh so
hence to that extent I think uh is where
we have been able to deliver both on
growth as well as in so far as the loss
outcomes and that's something that we
are very very happy with and we are very
very positive uh when we kind of head
into uh FI 27. Um and as I said uh in
response to the earlier question is
there any change in the thought process
of any of our reserving philosophies of
reserving processes? Absolutely no. We
continue to maintain prudence. We
continue to maintain margins uh for any
levels of uncertaintity that we see in
any of the book and more so in the
context of motor third party which has
got a longtail uh uh longtail periods of
loss development. So hence to that
extent uh that's in response to the
point on motor third parties. uh to your
first point uh or to to the on the first
question with respect to the 49
crination in the value of investments. I
think this is what I kind of uh
mentioned even as a part of the opening
uh transcript. Uh we have a policy on
impairment of investments uh that we
kind of have in the context of uh equity
investment specifically and consequent
to what we have seen the market
conditions getting exhibited in quarter
four of this year. We have obviously
valuated stocks that we hold and bases
the policy that we have we have done an
impairment of about 49 crores. All of
this 49 crores is in with respect to the
policy on dimination in the value of
equity investments.
>> Yeah. Okay. So now the uh CV growth I
think you're absolutely right. Uh it's
done better but there are you know
multiple moving parts. I don't want to
get into details. We can do it probably
when we meet a vinach uh and talk about
it. uh we've done better but the overall
contribution of CV to the book has still
been range more at 22%.
uh you see multiple you know things and
there's one more aspect that's the cost
of acquisition that comes into play and
if we see moderation we see an
opportunity we are also scanning the
market adding new vectors and something
looks viable we end up doing it we've
also created a significant edge with the
with the market through a fleet
management system which we are working
for last almost uh you know 18 to 24
months and that has also started giving
us some bit of an advantage uh as to
what we can do in commercial vehicles uh
it's it's overarching it's still come
range bound and we do believe that the
overall growth in CV market also for H2
was at a reasonable level which we have
given in the numbers in the details
which also again presented us with an
opportunity to do what is required uh
overall on the practice side if you see
where ICS and Lombard is certainly
private car and two-heer is uh our you
know our strength but CV we continue to
uh exhibit uh a lot more intensity but
the outcome used to be moderate uh for
us and for last uh couple of quarters
it's come into play and I sincerely hope
that we'll have a similar trend going
forward next year or this year rather
>> thank you thank you
>> thank you our next question comes from
the line of Nishan Chawat from Kotup
please go ahead
Hi. Uh this is slightly open-ended. Uh
uh the regulator is uh you know looking
at uh uh you know newer set of
guidelines on commissions uh you know
probably capping commissions or
deferring them uh you know assuming that
you know this kind of leads to some
amount of tightening. How do you see
this impact on the industry and for
yourself? uh nish I think we've always
maintained you know uh an an environment
with uh where the regulator enforces it
in the past also we have said that there
are quite a few players who have sought
dispensation or have not followed the
guideline and that does not occur well
any tightening on a uniform basis across
the industry uh would place ICSL
at a significant advantage uh uh because
we've remained within the limits of
expense of management and uh if others
fall in this we can only see uh better
time ahead for us as an industry. the
the only thing that remains is uh it
should be practiced across the industry
at a uniform bas on a uniform basis
>> and
>> so it's a welcome sign uh if it comes
out we always also mention the fact that
we believe the expense of management
should be on a single slab basis so that
there's clarity of execution and let the
market forces decide as to what works
for each one of them every single
business line
>> so so what is the latest in terms of you
know regulatory engagement on EOM. Is
there any revision expected around the
corner along with this separately?
>> We can we can only say that whatever is
accessed by each one of you is what we
access and the we await for what the
regulator has in mind. We don't want to
do any second guessing but uh any
tightening on account of that would be
welcome by us because it puts the
industry in uh good path with respect to
policy holder and also for us as an
institution.
Got it. Got it. Thank you very much and
all the best.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you
ladies and gentlemen. We will take that
as a last question for today. I would
now like to hand the conference over to
Mr. Sanjie Mantri for closing comments.
Over to you sir.
>> Thank you so much for joining in. Uh we
look forward to the new financials the
renewed hope. We've definitely as a team
uh been excited as to how we've been
able to close H2 over H1 and more so Q4
over the rest of it. Uh we are positive
in terms of how things can work out for
general insurance industry at large and
with the reforms that the regulator has
put in place. Uh but at the same time we
hope that the the world moves to a in a
in a much more you know peaceful manner
in times to come. So thank you so much
and all the best to each one of you for
joining in. Thank you so much.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you on behalf of ICICI Lumbard
General Insurance Company Limited. That
concludes this conference. Thank you all
for joining us. You may now disconnect
your lines.